WOMAN: ! killed Sirius Black!
我角死了天狼星布莱克 !
MAN: He's back.
他回来了
MAN [ON RADIO]: The police are continuing with the investigation...
警方继续调查…
...into the cause of the Millennium Bridge disaster.
千禧桥炎准的原因
Traffic has been halted as police search for survivors.
〈哈利波特 : 被选中的人? )
The surrounding area remains closed.
卷近地区也遭到封锁
The mayor has urged Londoners to remain calm....
伦敦市长呼税市民保持冷静
“Harry Potter.”
哈利波特
Who's Harry Potter?
哈利波特是谁?
Oh, no one.
谁也不是
Bit of a tosser, really.
活像个小大蛋
Funny, that paper of yours.
你拿的报纸有龟
Couple nights ago, I could've sworn I saw a picture move.
我发葡几天前看到照月移动
-Really? -Thought I was going around the twist.
-真的吗? -我还以为我眼花了
-Hey, 1 was wondering-- -Eleven. That’s when I get off.
-工工点，我1 工点下班
You can tell me all about that tosser Harry Potter.
你可以告诉我哈利波特的一切
DUMBLEDORE: You've been reckless this summer, Harry.
你这暑假到处阅宰，哈利
HARRY: I like riding around on trains.
我喜欢坐火车到处妃晃
Takes my mind off things.
让我暂时忘记一些事
Rather unpleasant to behold, isn’t it?
很将看，对吧?
The tale is thrilling, if 1 say so myself.
我得承认，这故事括刺激的
But now is not the time to tell it.
但现在不是说故事的时候
Take my arm.
扶住我的手臂
Do as I say.
照我的话做
I just Apparated, didn't I?
我刚才现影了，兰吧?
Indeed. Quite successfully too, I might add.
没错，而且很顺利
Most people vomit the first time.
多半的人第一次都会哎
I can’t imagine why.
我想不出理由
DUMBLEDORE: Welcome to the charming village of Budleigh Babberton.
坎迎光栈巴利巴柏顿村谈
Harry, assume, right about now, you must be wondering why I brought you here.
哈利，我想你一定在猜 我为什么带你来这里 ?
Am I right?
对吧?
Actually, sir, after all these years, I just sort of go with it.
这刻多年来我已经习惯了
Wands out, Harry.
拿出你的魔杖
[WHISPERING] Horace?
赫瑞司?
Merlin’s beard!
梅林的明子 !
No need to disfigure me, Albus.
你不必刺我川，阿不思 !
[IN NORMAL TONE] Well, I must say you make a very convincing armchair, Horace.
我必须说你化身成椅子担像的
It’s all in the upholstery. 1 come by the stuffing naturally. What gave me away?
我天生就有很大的袍整 什么滤露了我的侈装 ?
Dragon's blood.
龙血
-Oh. DUMBLEDORE: Oh, yes, introductions.
噢，不
Harry, I'd like you to meet an old friend and colleague of mine...
哈利，我的老友和老同事
...Horace Slughorn.
赫瑞司史拉囊
Horace...
赫瑞司…
... well, you know who this is.
你知道他是谁
SLUGHORN: Harry Potter.
哈利波特
DUMBLEDORE: What's with all the theatrics, Horace?
你做这广多侈装干嘛?
You weren't, by any chance, waiting for someone else?
你不会是在等别人吧?
Someone else? I'm sure I don't know what you mean.
别人? 我不懂你的意思
All right, the Death Eaters have been trying to recruit me for over a year.
好啦，食死人一直想招幕我
Do you know what that's like?
你知道有多恐怖吗?
You can only say no so many times, so I never stay anywhere more than a week.
你只能拒绝那些食死人炮次 所以我每星期会搬一次家
Muggles who own this are in the Canary Islands.
这房子的麻丰主人在加那利岛
Well, I think we should put it back in order for them, don’t you? Mind.
-那我们就该营他们恢复原状 -当心
That was fun.
真好玩
-Do you mind if I use the loo? -No, of course.
-我能借用洗手癌吗? -当然可以
Don’t think I don’t know why you're here, Albus.
别以为我不知道你来的目的
The answer's still no. Absolutely and unequivocally, no.
理所当然，和优良置疑
You're very like your father.
你跟你父亲很像
-Except for the eyes. You have your-- -My mother’s eyes. Yeah.
-除了眼睛，你遗传了… -我母亲的眼睛
Lily. Lovely Lily. She was exceedingly bright, your mother.
莉莉 美梦大方的莉莉
Even more impressive when one considers she was Muggle-born.
你的母亲隐明绝顶 她来自麻瓜家庭就更了不起
One of my best friends is Muggle-born. Best in our year.
我的好友也来自脐瓜家庭 她是我这年级最优秀的学生
Please don’t think I'm prejudiced. No, no.
我不是有偏见，划没有
Your mother was one of my absolute favorites. Look, there she is.
你母亲是我最逛过的学生 看看她
Right at the front.
就在前面
All mine. Each and every one.
每一个人都是我的学生
Ex-students, 1 mean.
我是说前任学生
You recognize Barnabas Cuffe, editor of The Daily Prophet.
你应该认得巴拿马斯古费 《预言家日报》的编辑
Always takes my owl, should I wish to register an opinion on the news of the day.
我给他的意见，他一定会区
Gwenog Jones, captain of the Holyhead Harpies.
天娜玉斯，霍利黑德哈比队
Free tickets whenever I want them.
我要免费门票，她一定给
Of course, I haven't been to a match in some time.
不过我好久没看魁地奇球赛
Ah, yes.
对了
Regulus Black.
狂子阿尔发布莱克
You no doubt know of his older brother Sirius. Died a few weeks ago.
你一定认识他的哥哥天狼星 狼个礼拜前才去世
I taught the whole Black family, except Sirius.
除了他以外，我教过他们全家
It's a shame. Talented boy.
真可惜，他很有天份
I got Regulus when he came along, of course, but I'd have liked the set.
我曾是狮子阿尔发的老师 但我很想当他们全家的老师
DUMBLEDORE: Horace?
赫瑞司?
Do you mind if ! take this?
这本订计可以给我吗?9
-I do love knitting patterns. -Yes, of course. But you’re not leaving?
-我很喜欢编织样式 -没问题，你要走了吗?
I think I know a lost cause when I see one. Regrettable.
我看得出你不原意重出江湖 真可惜
I would have considered it a personal triumph...
要是你答应回到霍格药奖…
...-had you consented to return to Hogwarts. Oh, well.
我会认为是我的个人成就
You're like my friend Mr. Potter here, one of a kind.
但你和波特先生一样特立独行
Well, bye-bye, Horace.
再见了，赫瑞司
Bye.
再见了
All right. I'll do it.
好啦，我答应就是了
But I want Professor Merrythought’s old office, not the water closet I had before.
但我要梅乐思教授的得办公室 不是之前的那间扁所
And I expect a raise. These are mad times we live in. Mad!
而且我要加薪! 这些日子很危险，超危险 !
They are indeed.
一点也没错
HARRY: Sir, exactly what was all that about?
校长，你为什么要我陪你去?
You are talented, famous and powerful. Everything Horace values.
你有才苇，有名气，又有力量 全都是圭瑞司最重视的
Professor Slughorn is gonna try to collect you, Harry.
史拉画教授会想收你为徒
You would be his crowning jewel.
你会是他最得意的门生
That's why he’s returning to Hogwarts. And it's crucial he should return.
所以他才答麻回到霍格华辫 而且请他回去非常重要
l fear I may have stolen a wondrous night from you, Harry.
很抱歉害你失去美好约会
She was, truthfully, very pretty, the girl.
说真的，那个美女真的很漂亮
It’s all right, sir. I'll go back tomorrow, make some excuse.
没关像，我会回去编个藉口
Oh, you'll not be returning to Little Whinging tonight, Harry.
你今晚不会回去小惠因
But, sir, what about Hedwig? And my trunk?
嘿美和我的行李箱怎入办 ?
Both are waiting for you.
它们都在等著你
Hedwig.
味美
Mum?
杂?
Ginny, what is it?
金妮，怎和了?
I was only wondering when Harry got here.
我只是在猜哈利是帮时到的
-What? Harry? Harry who? -Harry Potter, of course.
-什么 ? 哈利? 站个哈利呀? -当然是哈利波特吗
I think I'd know if Harry Potter was in my house, wouldn't I?
他到我家我应该知道才央
-His trunk’s in the kitchen, and his owl. -No, dear, I seriously doubt that.
-他的行李箱和玫头魔都在府房 -亲党的，不可能
Harry? Did someone say "Harry"?
哈利? 有人说哈利吗?
GINNY: Me, nosy. Is he up there with you?
是我啦，他嘴你在一起吗?
Of course not. I'd know if my best friend was in my room, wouldn't 1?
当然没有 我的兄弟来了，我应该知道
HERMIONE: Is that an owl? GINNY: You haven't seen him, have you?
-我孤见猎头魔的瑶音 环没看到他吧 ?
He’s wandering about the house.
当然了，他在屋子里乱晃
HERMIONE: Really? RON: Really.
-真的吗? -真的
MOLLY: Harry!
哈利!
What a lovely surprise.
真是令人高惧的乎喜 !
Why didn't you let us know you were coming?
你怎么不说你要来?
-I didn’t know. Dumbledore. -Oh, that man.
我也不知道，都是如不利多啦 真拿他没准法
But then, what would we do without him?
不过我们没有他又不行
Got a bit of toothpaste.
你脸上沾到牙膏
So when did you get here?
你是怒时来的?
A few days ago.
多天前
Though for a while, l wasn't sure I was coming.
我考虑过，本来不想来
Mum sort of lost it last week.
我始上礼拜差点发狂
Said Ginny and I had no business going back to Hogwarts.
她说我和金妮不该回埠格鞋兹
That it’s too dangerous.
那里太危险了
-Oh, come on. -She’s not alone.
-拜旗 -不是只有她这广想
Even my parents, and they're Muggles, know something bad’s happening.
我爸杂是麻扑都知道会出事
Anyway, Dad stepped in, told her she was being barmy...
幸好老爸出面 跟好说她只是神经紧张…
...and it took a few days, but she came around.
过绑天她就会没事
But this is Hogwarts we're talking about. It’s Dumbledore. What could be safer?
我们说的是堆格桂兹 有才不利多在最安全了
There’s been a lot of talk recently that...
最近大家都在说…
...Dumbledore’s got a bit old.
如不利多老了
Rubbish! Well, he’s only....
乱讲! 他只是…
What is he?
他到底怒茂呀?
Hundred and fifty? Give or take a few years.
1 5 0芯吧，加沽狗哉
BELLATRIX: Cissy! You can't do this! He can’t be trusted!
甸仙 工别找他，不能信任他 !
NARCISSA: The Dark Lord trusts him.
黑魔王信任他
BELLATRIX: The Dark Lord’s mistaken. -Pfft.
那广黑魔王就搞错了
SNAPE: Run along, Wormtail.
点尾，下去吧
I know I ought not to be here.
我知道我不该来的
The Dark Lord himself forbade me to speak of this.
黑魔王不准我说这件事
If the Dark Lord has forbidden it, you ought not to speak.
既然如此，就不该说
Put it down, Bella. We mustn't touch what isn’t ours.
放下来，贝拉 不是我们的东西不准碰
As it so happens, I'm aware of your situation, Narcissa.
水仙，我知道你的状涡
BELLATRIX: You?
你知道?9
The Dark Lord told you?
黑魔王跟你说通?
Your sister doubts me.
你的姐妹怀疑我
Understandable. Over the years I've played my part well.
这能理解，我一直都装得很像
So well, I've deceived one of the greatest wizards of all time.
我骗过史上最伟大的巫师之一
[BELLATRIX SNORTS]
如不利多是伟大巫师 白流才会质疑他
I don't doubt you, Severus.
我不怀疑你的串奥，赛佛勒斯
You should be honored, Cissy. As should Draco.
你该感到光荣，跨哥也一样
He’s just a boy.
他只是个孩子
I can’t change the Dark Lord’s mind.
我不能改释黑魔王的心意
But it might be possible for me to help Draco.
不过我也许能帮助践哥
NARCISSA: Severus. -Swear to it.
-赛佛勒斯 -你要发阔
Make the Unbreakable Vow.
说出不能下背的普言
It's just empty words.
他只会空口说白话
He'll give it his best effort.
假装慢力而为
But when it matters most...
当我们真的需要他
..-he’ll just slither back into his hole.
他就会缩回他的蛇洞
Coward.
情夫
Take out your wand.
把魔杖拿出来
Will you...
你…
... Severus Snape...
赛佛勒斯石内卜…
...-watch over Draco Malfoy...
当他企图完成黑魔王的任务
...as he attempts to fulfill the Dark Lord’s wishes?
原意照顾践哥马份吧?
And will you, to the best of your ability...
你也愿意间画所能…
..-protect him from harm?
保护他不受伤害吗?
BELLATRIX: And if Draco should fail...
菌一践哥任务失败
..-Will you yourself carry out the deed...
你原意亲自完成黑魔王…
...the Dark Lord has ordered Draco to perform?
命令践哥做的事吗?
Step up! Step up! We've got Fainting Fancies!
来咀，来喔! 我们有和理幻糖 !
Nosebleed Nougats!
鼻血牛扎糖 !
-And just in time for school.... -Puking Pastilles!
-趁开学以前超快买 -哎吐糖 !
-Into the cauldron, handsome.
-靓仔，大吐特旺吧
FEMALE VOICE: ! will have order!
大家要守秩序 !
! really hate children. f will have order!
我最讨厥小孩子 ! 大家要守秩序
-Peruvian Instant Darkness Powder. -A real money spinner, that.
-秘鲁瞬间黑暗粉 -这玩意儿超好器
Handy if you need to make a quick getaway.
和急著逃跑超有用
GEORGE: Hello, ladies. FRED: Hello, ladies.
-十位小姐好
-Love potions, eh? -Yeah, they really do work.
-想买党情赶药吗?9 -真的很有效哦
Then again, the way we hear it, sis, you're doing just fine on your own.
不过阿妹呀，我聘说 你靠自己也行
Meaning?
-什么意思? -虹不是和丁汤斑斯交往吧?
It's none of your business.
这不关你的事
RON: How much for this?
多少俩?
-Five Galleons.
-五加隆
-How much for me?
-你要算我多少?
I'm your brother.
我是你们的弟弟啊
-Ten Galleons.
-十加隆
RON: Come on, let’s go.
来吧，我们走
Hi, Ron.
路，荣思
Hi.
嗨
HERMIONE: How are Fred and George doing it? Half the Alley’s closed down.
弗雷和乔治是怎麻做到的? 斜角埠有一半都被封锁
RON: Fred reckons people need a laugh these days.
弗雷觉得这时候更需要炊笑
HARRY: Il reckon he's right.
我猜他没错
HERMIONE: Oh, no.
噢，不
Everyone got their wands from Ollivander’s.
大家都向奥利凡德买魔杖
Harry?
哈利?
Is it me, or do Draco and Mummy look like two people who don’t want to be followed?
是我看错了 还是跋哥和妈杂不想被跟跌?
LUNA: Quibbler.
《请论家》?
He’s lovely. They’ve been known to sing on Boxing Day, you know.
他超可爱的 他们会在季礼日唱歌
-Quibbler? -Oh, please.
-《雇论家》? -好的
-What's a Wrackspurt? -They’re invisible creatures.
-哈哈赴是什么? -和拖们是隐形的生物
They float in your ears and make your brain go fuzzy.
会飞进耳条让人脑佬糊涂
Quibbler.
《裹论家》 ? 《谓论家》?
RON: So, what was Draco doing with that weird-looking cabinet?
践哥拿著那奇怪的术楚干嘛?
And who were all those people?
还有那些人是谁呀?
Don't you see? It was a ceremony, an initiation.
你们看不出来吗 ? 这是一场典礼，一场八式
Stop it, Harry. I know where you're going.
别说了，我知道你想说什么
It's happened. He's one of them.
灶了，他成为他们的一份子
One of what?
谁的一份子?9
Harry is under the impression Draco Malfoy is now a Death Eater.
哈利认为践哥马份变成食死人
You're barking.
你别乱讲话
What would You-Know-Who want with Malfoy?
那个人要表份这灿人干嘛?
Well, then what’s he doing in Borgin and Burkes? Browsing for furniture?
他到波金与伯克氏的店干嘛? 想买家具吗?
It's a creepy shop. He's a creepy bloke.
那家店超丽怖，他也很丽怖
Look, his father is a Death Eater. It only makes sense.
他父亲是食死人，这很合理
Hermione saw it with her own eyes.
而且妙时亲眼看见
I told you, I don’t know what I saw.
我说过，我不知道我看见什和
MAN: Don't worry. When we get to Hogwarts, we'll sort it out.
别担心 我们到了鹤格村兹就会搞定
DRACO: What was that? Blaise? BLAISE: Don’t know.
-怎庆回事? 籍比? -我不知道
PANSY: Relax, boys. It’s probably just a first-year messing around.
别和紧张，大概只是一年级生在搞鬼
Come on, Draco. Sit down. We'll be at Hogwarts soon.
过来，坐下 很快就会到霍格鞋兹
Hogwarts. What a pathetic excuse for a school.
霍格革兹 这算是什么学校?
I'd pitch myself off the Astronomy Tower...
要是我得再待两年
. if [had to continue for another two years.
我就会从天文塔忠下来
What's that supposed to mean?
那是什么意思?
Let's just say I don’t think you'll see me wasting my time in Charms class next year.
姑且说明年你不会看到我 在那间魔法学院再浪费一年
Amused, Blaise?
你在笑我，刊比?
We'll see just who's laughing in the end.
等著看最后笑的会是谁
You two go on. I wanna check something.
你们先去吧，我想查探一下
Where's Harry?
哈利呢?
He’s probably already on the platform. Come on.
大概还在月台，来吧
DRACO: Didn’t Mummy ever tell you it was rude to eavesdrop, Potter?
你姻没教过你不准偷匠吗?
Petrificus Totalus.
整整石化 !
Oh, yeah...
对哦…
...she was dead before you could wipe the drool off your chin.
你逮是个婴孩时你妈就死了
That's for my father. Enjoy your ride back to London.
这是蔡我爸报做 祝你一路回伦敦安全顺利
Finite.
焉止 !
-Hello, Harry. -Luna!
-你好，哈利 -露娜 !
-How'd you know where I was? -Wrackspurts. Your head's full of them.
-姑怎夭知道我在这儿? -你满脑子都是喻喻震
HARRY: Sorry I made you miss the carriages, by the way, Luna.
对了，抱骨害代错过马车
LUNA: That’s all right. It was like being with a friend.
没关俐 这就像跟朋友在一起
Oh, I am your friend, Luna.
我是你的朋友呀，露娜
That's nice.
你真好
About time. I’ve been looking all over for you two.
终於到了“，我一直在找你们
Right. Names?
好吧，姓名?
Professor Flitwick, you've known me for five years.
季立维教授，你认识我五年了
No exceptions, Potter.
没有例外' 波特
Who are those people?
那些人是谁呀?
Aurors. For security.
正气师，为了维访安全
What's this cane here, then?
你拿著这根视子干嘛?
DRACO: It’s not a cane, you cretin. It’s a walking stick.
这不是棍子，这是手杖
Could be construed as an offensive weapon.
这被视为攻击武器
It’s all right, Mr. Filch. l can vouch for Mr. Malfoy.
没关你，屡七先生 我可以替马份先生担保
DRACO: Nice face, Potter.
波特，你的脸好正
Would you like me to fix it for you?
你要我花你医番好吗?
Personally, 1 think you look a bit more devil-may-care this way...
我觉得你这样比较有型
...but it’s up to you.
不通你自己决定
Well, have you ever fixed a nose before?
你棕人恬治过鼻子吗?
No, but I've done several toes, and how different are they, really?
没，不过我治过禾根脚趾 反正没什么差别，对吧?
-Episkey. -Ah!
复复元
-How do I look? -Exceptionally ordinary.
-我看起来怎样? -超普通
Brilliant.
太好了
RON: Don't worry. He'll be here in a minute.
放心，他马上就会来
Will you stop eating?
拜旗你别再吃了
Your best friend is missing!
你最好的朋友失距了啦
GINNY: He’s covered in blood again.
他脸上又全都是血
-Why is it he’s always covered in blood? -Looks like it’s his own this time.
-他为什么老是满脸血? -看来这次是他自己的血
Where have you been?
你去了哪里了
-What happened to your face? -Later.
-你的脸怎和了? -待会再说
What’ve I missed?
我错过什么 ?
Sorting Hat urged us all to be brave and strong in these troubled times.
分类帽要我们有危机时更勇敢
Easy for it to say, huh? It's a hat, isn’t it?
说得很容易，它只是一顶避子
DUMBLEDORE: Very best of evenings to you all.
-大家晚安 -谢了
First off, let me introduce the newest member of our staff...
首先，容我介绍 最新的教职员成员…
...Horace Slughorn.
赫瑞司史拉囊
Professor Slughorn, I'm happy to say...
我很高典史拉素教授
...has agreed to resume his old post as Potions Master.
同意再度担任魔药学教授
Meanwhile, the post of Defense Against the Dark Arts...
石办卜教授将负责传授
...Will be taken by Professor Snape.
黑魔法防冤街
DUMBLEDORE: Now, as you know...
你们都知道
..-each and every one of you was searched upon your arrival here tonight.
今晚你们来的时候都被搜身
And you have the right to know why.
你们有权利知道原因
Once there was a young man, who, like you...
有一个像你们一样的青少年
...sat in this very hall...
曾经坐在这座大廉
...walked this castle’s corridors, slept under its roof.
行走在古堡走廊 在这个屋敌下睡觉
He seemed to all the world a student like any other.
他看起来和别的学生没雨样
His name?
他的名字?
Tom Riddle.
汤姆瑞斗
Today, of course...
当然了，今天…
.-he’s known all over the world by another name.
世人只知道他另一个名字
Which is why, as I stand looking out upon you all tonight...
所以我必须每晚都保护你们
...[’m reminded of a sobering fact.
因为我知道这个可怕事实
Every day, every hour...
每天，每小时
...this very minute, perhaps...
甚至每分饶
...dark forces attempt to penetrate this castle’s walls.
黑暗势力都企图攻人进来
But in the end, their greatest weapon is you.
但是他们的终极武器是你们
Just something to think about.
我要你们好好想一想
Now, off to bed. Pip-pip.
上床睡党吧，快去 !
RON: That was cheerful.
他真会过人关心
History of Magic is upstairs, ladies, not down.
魔法史是在楼上，不是楼下
Mr. Davies! Mr. Davies! That is the girls’ lavatory.
戴维斯先生，戴维斯先生 ! 这是女生遍所
Potter.
波特
Oh, this can’t be good.
这不会是好事
Enjoying ourselves, are we?
你很享受嘛，是吗?
-l had a free period this morning, professor. -So I noticed.
-我时上有一堂自修课 -我注意到了
l would think you would want to fill it with Potions.
我以为你会去魔药学课劣区
Or is it no longer your ambition to become an Auror?
还是你不想当正气师了?
It was, but I was told I had to get an “Outstanding” in my O.W.L.
不过我得达到仪出巫和本等级
So you did, when Professor Snape was teaching Potions.
那是石内卜教授的要求 不过史拉碍教授很乐意接受
However, Professor Slughorn is perfectly happy to accept N.E.W.T.s students...
超级疲劳费炸正本测验…
...with "Exceeds Expectations.”
成绩超乎期待的学生
Brilliant. Um....
好极了
-Well, I'll head there straightaway. -Oh, good, good.
-那我这就去了 -很好
Potter, take Weasley with you. He looks far too happy over there.
波特，带卫斯理一起去 他看起来太开心了
RON: I don’t wanna take Potions.
可是我不想上魔药学课
This is Quidditch trials coming up. I need to practice.
魁地奇球队就快选秀 我得加紧张吧
SLUGHORN: Attention to detail in the preparation is the prerequisite of all planning.
准备的时候注意细节 是所有计划的最基本要求
Harry, my boy, I was beginning to worry. We've brought someone with us, I see.
哈利，我开始蔡你担心 你带了另外一个人
Ron Weasley, sir.
我是荣因卫斯理
But I'm dead awful at Potions, a menace, actually.
我每灵上魔玩学课都会出事
-I’m gonna.... SLUGHORN: Nonsense, we'll sort you out.
-所以我最好还是… -胡说八道，我会把你教好
Any friend of Harry's is a friend of mine. Get your books out.
哈利的朋友就是我的朋友 把课本拿出来
HARRY: I haven't actually got my book yet, and nor has Ron.
抱歉，我和沫恩都没有课本
Get what you want from the cupboard.
没关像，到栖子里拿课本
Now, as I was saying, I prepared some concoctions this morning.
我今天早上涂人备了一些魔药
Any ideas what these might be?
谁知道这些是什么吗 ?
-Yes, Miss...? -Granger, sir.
-是的 ， 娩是… ?9 -格荫像
That one there is Veritaserum. It’s a truth-telling serum.
这是吐真剂，能让人说实话
And that would be Polyjuice Potion.
这应该是变形水
It’s terribly tricky to make.
非常难调配
And this is Amortentia...
这是意乱情迷水
...the most powerful love potion in the world.
世上最强的爱情者药
It’s rumored to smell differently to each person according to what attracts them.
每个人过并的味道都不同
For example, I smell...
比如说，我最党并…
... freshly mown grass, and new parchment, and...
新割的草，全新的羊度纸…
...-spearmint toothpaste.
还有薄荷口味牙过
SLUGHORN: Now, Amortentia doesn’t create actual love. That would be impossible.
意乱情迷水不能让人得到真光 那是不可能的事
But it does cause a powerful infatuation or obsession.
但是可以盘造很强烈的… 迷矶或是著魔
And for that reason, it is probably the most dangerous potion in this room.
也因为如此 这应该是最危险的魔药
Sir? You haven't told us what’s in that one.
教授，你还没说这是什么?
Oh, yes.
是了
What you see before you, ladies and gentlemen...
各位同学，你们限前的是…
...is a curious little potion known as Felix Felicis.
被称为福来福训的魔各
But it is more commonly referred to as--
不过大家都称之为…
-Liquid luck. -Yes, Miss Granger. Liquid luck.
-幸运水 -没错，格将伯同学，幸运水
Desperately tricky to make, disastrous should you get it wrong.
超难调配，调错了会大灼国头
One sip and you will find that all of your endeavors succeed.
只要喝一口 你就会事事如意
At least until the effects wear off.
直到药效过了为目
So this is what I offer each of you today.
这是我今天给你们的奖品
One tiny vial of liquid luck to the student who, in the hour that remains...
只要你们能在一小时内
... Manages to brew an acceptable Draught of Living Death...
调配出一饮活死水 就能得到一小瓶幸运水
...the recipes for which can be found on page 10 of your books.
配方就在课本第十页
I should point out, however, only once did a student manage to brew a potion...
不过我要强调一点 调配出最好的一饮活死水…
...of sufficient quality to claim this prize.
才能得到这个奖品
Nevertheless, good luck to you all.
不管怎样，祝你们幸运
Let the brewing commence.
开始调配吧
How did you do that?
你是怎庆做到的?
You crush it. Don’t cut it.
要用压的，不能用切的
No. The instructions specifically say to cut.
不对，指示明明褒要用切的
No, really.
不，我是说真的
Merlin’s beard! It is perfect.
梅林的明子 !
So perfect I daresay one drop would kill us all.
太完美了 我敢说只要一滴就能角死大家
So here we are, then, as promised.
拿去吧，我一向守详言
One vial of Felix Felicis.
一瓶幸运水
Congratulations.
恭喜了
Use it well.
你要好好地用
DUMBLEDORE: Harry, you got my message. Come in.
哈利，你收到了通知，进来
How are you?
你好吗?
I'm fine, sir.
我很好， 校长
Enjoying your classes?
喜欢你上的课吗?
I know Professor Slughorn is most impressed with you.
史拉柬教授认为你表现最好
l think he overestimates my abilities, sir.
他高估了我的能力
Do you?
是吧?
Definitely.
绝对是
What about your activities outside the classroom?
你的课外活动呢?
-Sir? -Well, I notice you spend...
-校长? -我注意到…
...a great deal of time with Miss Granger.
你常和格苦八在一起
I can’t help wondering....
我忍不住要想…
Oh, no, no. I mean, she’s brilliant, and we're friends, but, no.
不…不…她很优秀 我们是好友，但我们不过电
Forgive me. 1 was merely being curious.
原文我，我只是好奇而已
But enough chitchat.
我们于聊金了
You must be wondering why I summoned you here tonight.
你一定在想我为什么把你找来
The answer lies here.
答案就在这壬
What you are looking at are memories.
这些全都是记居
In this case, pertaining to one individual, Voldemort...
这都是一个人的记居 佛地魔
...or, as he was known then, Tom Riddle.
当时他叫汤姆瑞斗
This vial contains the most particular memory...
这个小瓶装的是…
...of the day I first met him.
我第一天见到他的记居
I'd like you to see it, if you would.
你原意的话，我想给你看
WOMAN: { admit some confusion upon receiving your letter, Mr. Dumbledore.
我收到你的信有点搞不清状涡
In all the years Tom's been here, he’s never once had a family visitor.
汤姆来了这庆多年 从来没有家属来探访
There have been incidents with the other children. Nasty things.
他和其他小朋友关得不愉快 非常不愉快
Tom, you have a visitor.
汤姆，你有芒客
How do you do, Tom?
汤姆，你好吗?
Don't.
别碰我
-You’re the doctor, aren't you? -No.
-你是个医生，对吧? --不
l am a professor.
我是个教授
I don't believe you.
我不相信你
She wants me looked at.
她要找医生巷我检查
They think I’m different.
他们觉得我… 人
Well, perhaps they're right.
也许他们说的对
I'm not mad.
我莫没有发况
Hogwarts is not a place for mad people.
韦格苇兹不收疯子当学生
Hogwarts is a school.
霍格华兹是一问学校
A school of magic.
一 问魔法学校
You can do things, can’t you, Tom?
你会做一些事，对吧?
Things other children can’t.
其他小朋友不会做的事
I can make things move without touching them.
我可以不碰东西就让它移动
I can make animals do what ! want without training them.
我要动物做什么怨们就会做
l can make bad things happen to people who are mean to me.
我也能对付对我不好的人
I can make them hurt...
只要我想要
. if l want.
我可以让他们受伤
Who are you?
你是谁?
Well, I'm like you, Tom.
我跟你一檬，混姆
I'm different.
我也与办不同
Prove it.
证明给我看
I think there’s something in your wardrobe trying to get out, Tom.
有永西想从你的衣服里出来
Thievery is not tolerated at Hogwarts, Tom.
韦格苇兹不容许偷祯行为
At Hogwarts, you'll be taught not only how to use magic, but how to control it.
你不但会学会使用魔法 也要学会怎庆自制
You understand me?
你明白吗?
l can speak to snakes too.
我也能和蛇说话
They find me.
怨们会来找我
Whisper things.
跟我讲秘密
Is that normal for someone like me?
这对像我这种人正常吗?
Did you know, sir? Then?
你知道吗? 当时吗?
Did I know I'd just met the most dangerous dark wizard of all time? No.
我见到最危险的黑巫师? 不知道
Over time, while here at Hogwarts...
汤姆瑞斗在埠格甘区…
...Tom Riddle grew close to one particular teacher.
和一名教授走得特别近
Can you guess who that teacher might be?
你估到是哪一个吧?
You didn’t bring Professor Slughorn back simply to teach Potions, did you?
你把史拉柬教授找回来 不只是请他教魔本学，对吧?
No, I did not.
没错
You see, Professor Slughorn possesses something I desire very dearly.
他搓有一件我很想要的东西
And he will not give it up easily.
而且他不会轻易给我
You said Professor Slughorn would try to collect me.
你说史拉碍教授会想收我为徙
I did.
没错
Do you want me to let him?
你要我让他这刻做吗?
Yes.
是的
HARRY: All right. Um....
好吧
This morning, I’m gonna be putting you all through a few drills...
今天我会让你们集训
...just to assess your strengths.
加强你们的体力
Quiet! Please!
请安静 !
Shut it!
半踢 !
Thanks. All right. Um....
谢了，好了
Just because you made the team last year...
记住，你们去年加入球队
...does not guarantee you a spot this year. Is that clear?
不能保证今年也可以，明吗?
Good.
很好
No hard feelings, Weasley, all right?
别介意哦，和本斯理
Hard feelings?
别介意?
Yeah, I'll be going out for Keeper as well. It’s nothing personal.
我也要事取看守员的位子 范不是人针革你
Really? Strapping guy like you?
拜证，你这麻强半
You've got more of a Beater’s build, don't you think?
谭该当打出手，对吧?
Keepers need to be quick, agile.
看守员必须身手敏捷
Oh, I like my chances.
我的机会很大
Say, think you could introduce me to your friend Granger?
能替我介绍你朋友格苦人吗?
Wouldn't mind getting on a first-name basis, know what I mean?
我很想和她上于 你明邑?9
MAN 1: Come on, Weasley!
加油，昆思
WOMAN: Come on, Ron! MAN 2: Go on, Weasley!
加油，楷思 ! 加油，和本斯理 !
MAN 3: Go on, Weasley! MAN 4: Yeah, Ron!
加油，冠局 ! 加油，楷思 !
WOMAN: Come on, Ron!
加油，昆思
Confundus.
迷糊加
Isn't he brilliant?
他好强哦
I have to admit, I thought I was gonna miss that last one.
老实说，刚才我以为会抄不了
I hope Cormac’s not taking it too hard.
希望冠马不会太介意
He’s got a bit of a thing for you, Hermione. Cormac.
妙恤，寇马对有意思
He’s vile.
他超营人灰
HARRY: Have you ever heard of this spell? Sectumsempra?
你们匠过括消三步欠咒语吗?
No, I haven't.
没有
And if you had a shred of self-respect, you'd hand that book in.
你有自尊的话就该把书交出来
Not bloody likely. He’s top of the class.
想都别想，他是全班第一名
He’s even better than you, Hermione. Slughorn thinks he’s a genius.
他的成绩都比你高 史拉导认为他是天才
What?
什么?
I'd like to know whose that book was. Let's have a look.
我想知道那本书是谁的 让我们看看吧
No.
不行
HERMIONE: Why not?
为什么 ?
The binding is fragile.
它的装订缚快断了
HERMIONE: The binding is fragile? -Yeah.
-装订缚快断了? -对
-Who's the Half-Blood Prince? -Who?
-混血王子是谁? -谁?
That's what it says right here: "This book is property of the Half-Blood Prince.”
上面就是这刻高的 : 这本书属於混血王子
HERMIONE: For weeks you carry around this book, practically sleep with it...
你这礼拜一直带著这本着 就速睡党也抱著
...yet you have no desire to find out who he is?
你名不想查出混血王子是谁?
HARRY: I didn’t say ! wasn't curious, and I don't sleep with it.
我没说我不好奇 我也没抱著它睡党
RON: Well, it’s true.
她说的是真的
I like a nice chat before I go to bed. Now all you do is read that bloody book.
我以前睡前都会跟你于聊 现在你只会看那本臭书
It’s just like being with Hermione.
你变得跟妙朴一榜了
HERMIONE: Well, ! was curious, so I went to--
我很好奇，所以就去了……
-The library. -The library. And?
-图书馆 -然后呢?
I couldn't find a reference anywhere to a Half-Blood Prince.
什么也查不到 没有和混血王子有关的资料
-There we go. That settles it, then. SLUGHORN: Filius!
-这件事就不必追查下去了 -菲力
I was hoping to find you in the Three Broomsticks!
我正想到三根据锅找你
No, emergency choir practice, I'm afraid, Horace.
不行，枚时有合唱团练唱 抱菊，赫瑞司
Does anyone fancy a Butterbeer?
谁想喝奶油啤酒?
A chum of mine was sledging down Claxby Hill.
我的兄弟从克考斯比山滑下来
We had a very long, homemade, Norwegian-style sledge....
我们用的是自盘拖威式雪要
HARRY: No, not there. Over here.
不，列过去
No, sit beside me.
坐我汰净
Okay.
好吧
MAN: Something to drink?
想喝点什么 ?
HERMIONE: Three Butterbeers, and some ginger in mine, please.
三杯奶油啤酒，我要加曹汗
Oh, bloody hell.
可蚂
Slick git.
大和猪头
Honestly, Ronald, they're only holding hands.
拜证，他们只是牵手而已
And snogging.
而且还在亲踢
-I'd like to leave. -What?
-我想走了 -什么?
You can't be serious.
你在开玩笑吧
-That happens to be my sister. -So?
-那可是我妹妹呢 -又怎榜?
What if she looked over here and saw you snogging me? You expect her to leave?
要是她看到你跟我亲踢 她会站起来走人吗?
SLUGHORN: Hey, my boy! HARRY: Hello, sir. Wonderful to see you.
-哈利，好像伙 -你好，很高洪见到你
And you, and you.
我也一样
So, what brings you here?
你怎订会跑来?
The Three Broomsticks and I go way back, further than I care to admit.
我好久以前就常来这儿 到底有多久我不想说
I can remember when it was One Broomstick.
我记得当时还叫一根据禹
All hands on deck, Granger. Listen, my boy, in the old days...
快把甲板探乾 隐好了，十早以前…
...l used to throw together the occasional supper party...
我会为一雨个被选中的学生…. .
..-for the select student or two.
偶尔开个晚餐派对
-Would you be game? -I’d consider it an honor, sir.
-你有机趣吗 ?
You would be welcome too, Granger.
你也能一起来，格苦俊
-I'd be delighted, sir. -Splendid. Look for my owl.
-我很乐意，教授 -太好了“，我会再通知你们
Good to see you, Wallenby.
很高内见到你，沫思
What are you playing at?
你搞紧哗?
Dumbledore’s asked me to get to know him.
如不利多要我和他混熟
-Get to know him? -I don’t know.
-多了解他吗? -不知道
It must be important. If it wasn’t, Dumbledore wouldn't ask.
这件事一定很重要 不然他不会要我这广做
Got a little bit....
你跑巴沾到一是…
LEANNE: Katie, you don’t know what it could be.
凯娣，人不知道是什么
RON [WHISPERING]: Harry. HARRY: What?
放心，我知道我在做什笨
RON: Did you hear what she was saying back at the pub about me and her snogging?
哈利，你在酒馆有没有聊到 她说要跟我亲跑的事?
HARRY: As if.
想都别想
I warned her. l warned her not to touch it.
我警告明她，我叫她不要碰
Don’t get any closer. Get back, all of you.
别著近，全都往和后退
Do not touch that, except by the wrappings. Do you understand?
除了包装纸，什条都不准碰 明白吗?
You're sure Katie did not have this in her possession...
你确定凯嫌进去三根据壳时
...when she entered the Three Broomsticks?
站没有拿著这玩意吗?
It’s like I said.
就像我说的那样
She left to go to the loo, and when she came back she had the package.
她跑去上遍所 回来的时候就拿著包囊
She said it was important that she deliver it.
她说她一定要交给一个人
-Did she say to whom? -To Professor Dumbledore.
-有说要交给谁吗? -好不利多教授
Very well. Thank you, Leanne. You may go.
很好，谢谢，人可以走了
Why is it when something happens it is always you three?
怎麻每次出事都有你们三个?
Believe me, professor, I’ve been asking myself the same question for six years.
相信我，这六年来我也在纳奖
McGONAGALL: Oh, Severus.
噢，赛佛勒斯
What do you think?
你觉得怎样了
I think Miss Bell is lucky to be alive.
中和小姐没有送命算是走运
She was cursed, wasn’t she?
她被下了顺，对吧?
I know Katie. Off the pitch, she wouldn't hurt a fly.
我了解凯娣，她不会伤害人
If she was delivering that to Dumbledore, she wasn't doing it knowingly.
要是她要把包囊交给如不利多 她自己一定不知道
Yes, she was cursed.
疫错，她被下了唤
It was Malfoy.
一定是马份
That is a very serious accusation, Potter.
这是很嘎属的指控，波特
Indeed.
没错
-Your evidence? -l just know.
-有证据吧? -我就是知道
You just...
你就是…
.. know.
知道
You astonish with your gifts, Potter.
你的才革又读我目瞪口呆
Gifts mere mortals can only dream of possessing.
凡人只能枕想撞有的芍世才药
How grand it must be to be the Chosen One.
当被选中的人一定感觉很伟大
I suggest you go back to your dormitories. All of you.
我建议你们回宿舍，全都回去
RON: What do you suppose Dean sees in her? Ginny?
你党得迪安看上人金妮哪一点 ?
Well, what does she see in him?
她又看上他哪一点 ?
Dean? He's brilliant.
迪安唉?9 他很优秀
You called him a slick git not five hours ago.
你五小时前才曙他大和猪头
Yeah, well, he was running his hands all over my sister, wasn't he?
当时他在对我妹上下其手
Something snaps, and you've gotta hate him, you know? On principle.
我有根筋断挤，不得不恨他 这是原则问题
Il suppose.
我猜是吧
-So, what is it he sees in her? -I don’t know.
-到底看上她哪一点 ? -我不知道
She's smart, funny.
她又陷明又幽软
-Attractive. -Attractive?
-且很漂亮 -漂亮?
-You know, she’s got nice skin. -Skin?
-的皮广超好 -皮庚?
Dean dates my sister because of her skin?
迪安为了我妹妹的皮庚追求她?
Well, no, 1 mean, I’m just saying it could be a contributing factor.
不是啦，这可能是一个原因
Hermione’s got nice skin.
妙蛙的皮庚也很嫩滑
Wouldn't you say? As skin goes, I mean.
你应该同意吧，就皮庚来说
I've never really thought about it.
我从来没有起过
But, I suppose, yeah.
不过我猜是吧
Very nice.
是很不错啦
-Il think I'll be going to sleep now. -Right. Yeah.
-要去睡觉了 -好吧
So tell me, Cormac, do you see anything of your Uncle Tiberius these days?
寇局，最近有看到你披披吗?
CORMAC: Yes, sir. In fact, I'm meant to go hunting with him...
有 这周末要跟他和…
..and the Minister for Magic over the holidays.
魔法部长的铺…
Well, be sure to give them both my best.
替我向他们问好
What about your uncle, Belby?
中责比，你权权哇?了
For those who don’t know, Marcus’ uncle invented the Wolfsbane Potion.
你们也许不知道 马卡的抄叔发明了缚狼汗
-ls he working on anything new? -Don’t know.
-在发明新玩意儿吗?9 -知道
Him and Dad don't get on. Probably because me dad says potions are rubbish.
他和老区合不来 大概因为我爸说缚狼汁是垃圾
Says the only potion worth having is a stiff one at the end of the day.
他说最好的魔药是睡前一杯酒 你呢，格苦八小姐?
What about you, Miss Granger? What does your family do in the Muggle world?
你的家人在友夭世界做什么?
My parents are dentists.
我爸妈都是牙医
They tend to people's teeth.
他们专门医治人们的牙商
Fascinating. And is that considered a dangerous profession?
那是一种危险的职业吗 ?
HERMIONE: No.
不是
Although, one boy, Robbie Fenwick, did bite my father once.
但有个小鬼罗比芬卫咬过我爸
He needed 10 stitches.
害我爸终了十针
[WHISPERS] Look at her eyes. They've been fighting again, her and Dean.
看看她的眼睛 她和迪安一定又吵架了
Sorry. I'm not usually late.
抱歉，我通常不会如到
No matter. You're just in time for dessert, that is, if Belby’s left you any.
没关像，正好来吃甜点 如果没被忠泵比吃完的话
HARRY: What?
什么?
Nothing.
没什让
SLUGHORN: Goodbye. Bye-bye.
再见，和拜拜
-Potter. -I'm sorry, sir.
-波特 -对不起
l was just admiring your hourglass.
我正在钦赏你的沙漏
SLUGHORN: Oh, yes.
是啊
A most intriguing object.
很有意思的东西
The sand runs in accordance with the quality of the conversation.
沙子按照交谈的内容往下漏
If it is stimulating, the sand runs slowly.
内容很精采，沙子就漏得很慢
-If it is not.... -I think I'll be going.
-要是不精采… -我想我该走了
Nonsense. You have nothing to fear, dear boy.
傻孩子，你没什么好怕的
As to some of your classmates...
你有些同学…
... well, let’s just say they're unlikely to make the shelf.
我只能说我不会收他们为徒
The shelf, sir?
收徒?
Anyone who aspires to be anyone hopes to end up here.
想要成名都得当我的徒弟
But then again, you already are someone, aren't you, Harry?
不过你已经成名了，和对吧?
Did Voldemort ever make the shelf, sir?
佛地魔当过你的徒弟吗?
You knew him, didn't you, sir, Tom Riddle? You were his teacher.
你认识他，混姆瑞斗，对吧? 你兽是他的老师
Mr. Riddle had a number of teachers whilst here at Hogwarts.
瑞斗先生在这里有很多老师
What was he like?
他是什么样的人?
I'm sorry, sir. Forgive me.
抱菊，请原该我
He killed my parents.
他角死我父母
It’s only natural you should want to know more.
想知道更多他的事
But I’m afraid I must disappoint you, Harry.
但是我必须让你失望
When I first met Mr. Riddle, he was a quiet...
我第一次见到瑞斗先生 他很安静…
. albeit brilliant, boy committed to becoming a first-rate wizard.
也很优秀 而且决心成为一流的巫师
Not unlike others I’ve known.
就跟其他学生没雨样
Not unlike yourself, in fact.
其实跟你也没十样
If the monster existed...
要是他有黑暗的一面…
...it was buried deep within.
也被深埋在内心深钼
Good luck, eh, Ron.
祝好运，紫恩
MAN 1: Nice hat! MAN 2: Ron, you're a loser.
-帽子万好看 -紫思，你好差劲
I'm counting on you, Ron. l have two Galleons on Gryffindor, yeah?
我计吗你啦 我赌十加隆葛来分多队会赢
WOMAN: Looking good, Ron. MAN 3: Loser!
方料到 !
What’s he wearing?
他穿的是什么呀?
RON: So how was it, then?
怎庆样 ?
-How was what? -Your dinner party?
-什么怎庆样 ? -了晚餐派对呀?
HERMIONE: Pretty boring, actually.
其实几无聊
Though I think Harry enjoyed dessert.
哈利疙鳃意最后的甜点
Slughorn’s having a Christmas do, you know.
史拉柬要闪避诈派对
And we're meant to bring someone.
我们要揣伴
l expect you'll be bringing McLaggen. He’s in the Slug Club, isn’t he?
我猜你会带寇马去吧 他不是也受史拉柬青睐吗?
-Actually, 1 was going to ask you. RON: Really?
-其实我想邀请你 -真的吗?
Good luck today, Ron.
祝你今天好运
I know you'll be brilliant.
我知道你一定会赢
I'm resigning. After today’s match, McLaggen can have my spot.
我要退出球队 以后就让寇局接我的位子
HARRY: Have it your way.
随你便
-Juice? -Sure.
-喝果汁吗? -好啊
Hello, everyone.
大家好
You look dreadful, Ron.
你看起来胡了
Is that why you put something in his cup?
所以你才在他的饮料加料?
Is it a tonic?
是不是药水?
HERMIONE: Liquid luck.
幸运水
Don’t drink it, Ron.
不要喝，莹思
-You could be expelled for that. -l don’t know what you're talking about.
-你会因此被退学呀 -我不知道你在说什么
Come on, Harry. We've got a game to win.
来吧，我们要赢这场比赛
Yes!
好耶!
MAN: Go on, Ron! Do it!
加油，楷思 !
CROWD [CHANTING]: Weasley! Weasley! Weasley!
好耶 工本思 !
Yes!
好耶!
Weasley! Weasley! Weasley!
本斯理…和本斯理…
You really shouldn't have done it.
你真的不该那庆做
I know. I suppose I could've just used a Confundus Charm.
我知道 我猜我可以只用迷糊加
That was different. That was tryouts. This was an actual game.
有什么不同，那是选拔赛 这是真正的比赛
You didn't put it in.
你兹没有个进去
Ron only thought you did.
荣因以为你有
Charms spell. I'm just practicing.
魔法咒话，我只是在冻吉
Well, they're really good.
名们看起来很像真的
How does it feel, Harry?
你有什么感觉?
When you see Dean with Ginny?
当你看到迪安和人金妮在一起?
I know.
我知道
Il see the way you look at her.
我看到你看她的样子
You're my best friend.
你是我最好的朋友
I think this room’s taken.
我猜这儿没空位了
What's with the birds?
那些高哪儿来的?
Oppugno.
生衡攻 !
It feels like this.
跟称的感党一样
Look, I can't help it if she’s got her knickers in a twist.
她生我的所我也没准法
What Lav and I have, well, let’s just say, there’s no stopping it.
我和文姐的关像 我只能说擅也抄不了
It’s chemical.
那是一种火花
Will it last? Who knows? Point is, I'm a free agent.
会持久吗 ?9 谁知道?
HERMIONE: He's at perfect liberty to kiss whoever he likes. I really couldn't care less.
他爱亲谁，是他的自由 我一点都不在乎
Was I under the impression he and I would be attending Slughorn’s Christmas party?
我是不是以为我和他… 会一起参加史拉毒的村诞派对
Yes.
是的
Now, given the circumstances, I've had to make other arrangements.
不过照现在的情况看来 我得另外找一个男伴
Have you?
人有找吗?
Yes. Why?
有，怎和了?
I just thought, seeing as neither of us can go with who we'd really like to...
既然我们不能和心上人一起去
...we should go together, as friends.
我们不如以朋友身分一起去
Why didn’t I think of that?
我怎庆没想到呢?
Who are you going with?
你要跟谁去?
Um, it’s a surprise.
这是个苞喜
Anyway, it’s you we've got to worry about. You can't just take anyone.
你比较令人担心 你不能随便找阿猫阿狗
See that girl over there?
看到那个女仔吗?
That's Romilda Vane. Apparently she’s trying to smuggle you a love potion.
那是路咪凡 她想偷偷向你下营情专药
Really?
真的吗?
Hey! She's only interested in you because she thinks you're the Chosen One.
她以为你是被选中的人 才会对你有机趣
But l am the Chosen One.
但是我是被选中的人呀
Okay, sorry. Um, kidding.
抱菊，开玩笑的啦
I'll ask someone I like.
我去找我喜欢的女生
LUNA: I've never been to this part of the castle.
我从来没来十堡的这壬
At least not while awake. I sleepwalk, you see.
至少不是醒著来过，我会移入
That's why I wear shoes to bed.
所以我都穿著鞋子睡觉
Harmonia Nectere Passus.
妙果受准咒
Drink?
喝水吗?
Neville.
奈威 !
I didn’t get into the Slug Club.
我没有进入史拉俱乐部
It’s okay, though. He’s got Belby handing out towels in the loo.
没关俐 他叫册贾比在男亢派毛中
-Oh, well, I'm fine, mate. Thanks. -Okay.
-我不渴，谢了 -好吧
Hermione. What are you doing? And what happened to you?
妙村，炼在干嘛? 你怎么了?
I've just escaped. I mean, left Cormac under the mistletoe.
我刚逃出来 我从榭寄生下逃礁了寇马
Cormac? That's who you invited?
寇马? 你的男伴是寇忆?
I thought it would annoy Ron the most.
我以为会菩履楷恩
SLUGHORN: Thank you. I'll catch up with you later.
多谢了，待会再来找你们
He’s got more tentacles than a Snarfalump plant.
他比入夏刚更多魔夏
-Dragon tartare? -No, I'm fine. Thank you.
-蒜靶生龙肉? -不要，谢了
Just as well. They give one horribly bad breath.
也好，吃了会口生
On second thoughts....
等一下
Might keep Cormac at bay.
这也许能阻止寇马
Oh, God, here he comes.
天啊，他来了
I think she just went to powder her nose.
她好像去女训福妆
CORMAC: Slippery little minx, your friend.
你朋友像个狐狸精
Likes to work her mouth too, doesn’t she?
而且嘴巴老是讲个不停
What is this I’m eating, by the way?
我吃的是什么 ?
Dragon balls.
龙蛋
You've just bought yourself a month's detention, McLaggen.
你要被留校查看一个月
Not so quick, Potter.
先别走，波特
Sir, l really think I should rejoin the party. My date....
我该回到派对了“，我的女伴…
Can surely survive your absence for another minute or two.
可以忍受你不在一，十分猎
Besides, I only wish to convey a message.
而且我只想传个话
-A message? -From Professor Dumbledore.
-传话? -好不利多要我向你问好
He asked me to give you his best, and he hopes you enjoy your holiday.
希望你假期玩得开心
You see...
他要…
...he’s traveling, and he won't return until term resumes.
去旅行，直到开学才会回来
Traveling where?
他要去哪里了
Take your hands off me, you filthy Squib!
把你的臭手拿开 !
FILCH: Professor Slughorn, sir.
史拉藉教授
Il just discovered this boy lurking in an upstairs corridor.
我发现这小子在楼上东张西望
He claims to have been invited to your party.
他说他有收到你的邀请
Okay, okay. I was gatecrashing. Happy?
好啦，我偷阅进来，行吗?
Certainly, professor.
请便，教授
All right, everyone, carry on, carry on.
大彩儿，继续玩吧
DRACO: Maybe I did hex that Bell girl. Maybe I didn't. What's it to you?
也许我向山娣下咒，也许没有 这关你什么事?
SNAPE: I swore to protect you.
我发获要保护你
I made the Unbreakable Vow.
我许下了不破普
DRACO: I don't need protection.
我不需要保护
l was chosen for this. Out of all others. Me.
那个人从这广多人之中选中我
-And I won't fail him. -You're afraid, Draco.
-我不会让他失望 -你很害怕，践哥
You attempt to conceal it, but it’s obvious. Let me assist you.
你想隐瞒，不过很明显 让我帮助你
DRACO: No!
不
l was chosen. This is my moment.
我被选中，这是我的机会
RON: “Unbreakable Vow.”
不破玖?9
You're sure that’s what Snape said?
你确定石内卜这庆说?
Positive. Why?
确定，为什么?
Well, it’s just you can’t break an Unbreakable Vow.
你不能这背不破闭
I'd worked that much out for myself, funnily enough.
不用你说我也猜得到
You don’t understand.
你不明白
Oh, bloody hell.
可蚂
I miss you.
我好想你
Lovely.
太好了
All she wants to do is snog me. My lips are getting chapped. Look.
她只起跟我亲嘴 我的噶诗都被磨破了
I'll take your word for it.
我相信你
So, what happens to you? What happens if you break an Unbreakable Vow?
你是怎庆了? 过背不破闭会怎样?
You die.
你就会死
WOMAN: Wait, the pudding’s still here.
还有布丁，放下来，我们要吃
REMUS: Voldemort has chosen Draco Malfoy for a mission?
佛地魔选中践哥马份执行任务
I know it sounds mad.
了贡超来很难以置信
Has it occurred to you Snape was simply pretending to offer Draco help...
也疾石内卜只是假装帮助践哥
-That’s not what it sounded like. NYMPHADORA: Perhaps Harry's right, Remus.
-匠起来花不是这样 -也许哈利说的对
To make an Unbreakable Vow, it’s--
我是说要发不破玖…
It comes down to whether or not you trust Dumbledore’s judgment.
重点是你信不信邮不利多
-Dumbledore trusts Snape, therefore I do. -Dumbledore can make mistakes.
如不利多信任石内直 所以我也信任他
You're blinded by hatred.
你被做恨蒙蔽了艇眼
-'m not. -Yes, you are.
-才没有 -你有
People are disappearing, Harry, daily.
每天都有风凰会会员失路
We place our trust in a handful of people.
我们只能信任少数人
If we start fighting amongst ourselves, we're doomed.
如果起内阅就完了
Open up, you.
张并跑巴
Don't you trust me?
你不信任我吗?
It’s good.
很好吃
RON: Yeah, I'll just-- Get-- Yeah.
好吧， 我去拿…
-Pie? -Not for me, no.
-馅人饼? -我不要
ARTHUR: You'll have to forgive Remus.
你得原旋路平
It takes its toll, his condition.
他的状况念来念爆
HARRY: Are you all right, Mr. Weasley?
卫斯理先生，你好吗?
We're being followed, all of us.
我们全都被跟路
Most days, Molly doesn't leave the house.
茉莉儿乎都足不出户
It’s not been easy.
日子真的很难芳
Did you get my owl?
你收到我的信吗?
Yes, I did.
收到了
If Dumbledore’s traveling, then that's news to the Ministry...
要是几不利多去旅行…
...but perhaps that’s the way Dumbledore wants it.
而魔法部毫不知情 也许这就是他的用意
As for Draco Malfoy...
至蕉践哥马份…
...[ know a bit more.
我知道得多一点
-Go on. -l sent an agent to Borgin and Burkes.
-请说 -我派表员到波金与伯克氏店
I think, from what you described...
以你的描述来看…
...what you and Ron saw in summer...
你和莹思看见的东西…
...the object that Draco is so interested in...
也是践哥这刻有从趣的东西
...is a vanishing cabinet.
一定是消失杭林
A vanishing cabinet?
消失杭模?
They were all the rage when Voldemort first rose to power.
佛地魔虽起和后开始薪为风潮
You can see the appeal. Should Death Eaters come knocking...
看得出它吸引人的地方 要是食死人找上门…
..-one simply had to slip inside and disappear for an hour or two.
躲进消失杭林就能逃遇一动
They can transport you anywhere.
它们能把你送到任何地方
Tricky contraptions though, very temperamental.
不过这玩意很脐烦，很难搞
What happened to it? The one at Borgin and Burkes?
波金与伯克氏店的怎庆了?
Nothing.
没怎床
It’s still there.
它还在店里
NYMPHADORA: It was delicious, Molly, really.
-大餐真的很好吃，茉莉 -你确定你不留下来?
No, we should go. The first night of the cycle’s always the worst.
我们该走了 过期的第一晚总是最难苑
Remus?
路平?
Sweetheart.
老公
Has Ron gone to bed?
某恩睡了吗?
Shoelace.
你的鞋带
Merry Christmas, Harry.
圣诞快乐，哈利
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
-Harry, no! -Remus!
-哈利，不! -路平 !
Ginny!
金妮 !
BELLATRIX: ¢ killed Sirius Black! ! killed Sirius Black!
我角死了天狼星布莱克 !
You coming to get me?
你要来找我报仇吗 ?
Harry, can you get me?
哈利?
Harry?
哈利!
Stupefy!
吊唱失!
Ginny!
金妮 !
Molly.
茉莉
HERMIONE: It’s easy for them to get to you.
他们想找到你很容易
You're bloody lucky you weren't killed. You have to realize who you are, Harry.
你没死算你走运 你必须知道你是谁
I know who I am, Hermione, all right?
我知道我是谁，好吧?
Sorry.
抱歉
Lav, come on. Of course I'll wear it.
文旭，我当然会戴
Excuse me, I have to go and vomit.
对不起，我得去吐了
SLUGHORN: !'d like to know where you get your information.
我想知道你的资讯是哪来的
More knowledgeable than half the staff, you are.
你比全校一半师生知道的更多
. is it true that Professor Merrythought is retiring?
真的要退休吗?9
Now, Tom. I couldn't tell you if 1 knew, could I?
汤姆，就算我知道也不能说
By the way, thank you for the pineapple. You're quite right, it is my favorite.
对了，谢谢你送的凤梨 你这孩子不错，我最过吃风梨
But how did you know?
不过你怎订会知道9
Intuition.
未我的直澡
SLUGHORN: Gracious. Is it that time already?
真是的，这广晚了吗?
Off you go, boys, or Professor Dippet will have us all in detention.
快去睡觉 不然狄艾教授会罚我们留堂
Look sharp, Tom. Don’t want to be caught out of bed after hours.
票子放亮点，混姆 小心别在熄焙和后被带到
-ls something on your mind, Tom? -Yes, sir.
-你有心事吗? -有
You see, I couldn't think of anyone else to go to.
我找不到别人可以倾诉
The other professors, well, they're not like you.
其他的教授，跟你不一样
They might misunderstand.
他们也许会误解
Go on.
亿管说吧
l was in the library the other night...
前线天晚上我在…
...in the Restricted Section...
图韦馆的禁区…
..and I read something rather odd about a bit of rare magic.
我读到一个罕见魔法的段落
And I thought perhaps you could illuminate me.
我在想也许你能蔡我解惑
It’s called, as 1 understand it....
以我的理解，它叫…
I beg your pardon?
什么?
I don’t know anything about such things, and if I did, ! wouldn't tell you!
我不知道那是什么 就算知道也不会告诉你
Now, get out of here at once, and don't let me ever catch you mentioning it again!
快给我出去 别被我发现你又提到这件事
DUMBLEDORE: Confused?
不明白咽?
I'd be surprised if you weren't.
我六不感到意外
Well, I don’t understand. What happened?
我不懂，和发生什么事?
This is perhaps the most important memory I've collected.
这或许是我范集最重要的记居
It is also a lie.
也是个议言
This memory has been tampered with...
这段记居遭到修改…
...by the same person whose memory it is, our old friend, Professor Slughorn.
而修改这段记居的人 就是当事人史拉泗教授
But why would he tamper with his own memory?
他为什么要修改自己的记居?
-l suspect he’s ashamed of it. -Why?
-我猜他是引以为了 -为什么 ?
Why, indeed?
问得好
l asked you to get to know Professor Slughorn, and you have done so.
我请你去多了解史拉兽教授
Now I want you to persuade him to divulge his true memory...
你也册我的话去做 现在我要你用任何方法…
.any way you can.
说服他说出他真正的记居
I don’t know him that well, sir.
我跟他冰没有那广熟
This memory is everything.
这段记居最重要
Without it, we are blind.
没有它就对付不了佛地魔
Without it, we leave the fate of our world to chance.
只能让命运决定世界的存亡
You have no choice.
你别乱选择
You must not fail.
绝对不能失败
SLUGHORN: So I'd highly recommend you reacquaint yourself...
我建议你们重读解药那一章
I'll tell you more about bezoars in our next class. Right, off you go.
下堂课会再多讨论羊旨石 下课吧
Alys, don’t forget your rat tail.
艾莉，别忘了和的鼠尾巴
To what do I owe this pleasure?
什么风把你吹来?
Sir, 1 wondered if l might ask you something.
我能不能问你一件事?
Ask away, dear boy, ask away.
问吧，亿管问
The other day ! was in the library, in the Restricted Section...
始天前我在图书馆的禁区…
..and 1 came across something rather odd about a very rare piece of magic.
发现一种很军见的魔法
Yes. And what was this rare piece of magic?
这种罕见的魔法是什么?
Well, I don’t know. l can’t remember the name exactly.
我不知道，我不记得名字了
It got me wondering, are there some kinds of magic you're not allowed to teach us?
这义起我的好奇心 有些魔法是不是不能教学生?
SLUGHORN: I'm Potions Master, Harry.
我是魔药学教授
l think your question'd better be posed to Professor Snape.
你应该去癌石内卜教授才关
HARRY: Yes. Um....
是啊
He and I don't exactly see eye to eye, sir.
可是我和他之问有嫌阶
What I mean to say is...
我想说的是…
... Well, he’s not like you.
他不像你
He might misunderstand.
他可能会误解
Yes. There can be no light without the dark.
没错，没有黑暗就没有光亮
And so it is with magic. Myself, I always strive to live within the light.
魔法也一样 我一向试著活在光亮之中
I suggest you do the same.
我建议你也这广做
Is that what you told Tom Riddle, when he came asking questions?
汤姆瑞斗来找你 你也这订说?
Dumbledore put you up to this, didn't he?
部不利多叫你来的，对吧?
Didn't he?
对不对?
Yes?
对吗?
Oh, it’s you, Potter.
原来是你自己
I'm sorry, I’m busy at the moment.
抱菊，我目前很忙
It’s beautiful, isn’t it? The moon.
月亮很美， 对吧?
HARRY: Divine.
美极了
Had ourselves a little late-night snack, did we?
你吃了点心，对吧?
It was on your bed, the box. I just thought I'd try one.
巧克力在你床上，我只想嗜哮
HARRY: Or 20. -l can’t stop thinking about her, Harry.
-你哮了20颗 -我没准法不去想她
Honestly, I reckoned she was annoying you.
我还以为你开始嫌她烦了
She could never annoy me.
我水下不会嫌她烦
I think I love her.
我想我爱她
Well, brilliant.
好极了
Do you think she knows I exist?
你想她知道我的存在吗 ?
I hope so. She's been snogging you for three months.
拜旗，她这三个月一直亲你
Snogging? Who are you talking about?
亲我? 你在说谁呀?
Who are you talking about?
你又在说谁?
Romilda, of course. Romilda Vane.
当然是四咪凡呀
Okay, very funny.
好吧，很好笑
-What was that for? -It’s no joke! I’m in love with her!
-你这是干嘛? -我不是开玩笑
Fine, you're in love with her. Have you ever actually met her?
我党上她了 好，你党上她，你见明她邑 ?
No. Can you introduce me?
没，你能介绍吗?
Come on, Ron. I’m gonna introduce you to Romilda Vane.
来吧，我介绍区味凡给你认识
I'm sorry, sir. 1 wouldn't bother you if it weren't absolutely essential.
抱歉，不重要的话我不会烦你
RON: Where's Romilda?
时味呢?
What's the matter with Wenby?
药萄这小子怎么了?
HARRY [WHISPERS]: Very powerful love potion.
被落了很强的党情雹药
SLUGHORN: Very well. Better bring him in.
好吧，把他带进来
I'd have thought you could whip up a remedy for this in no time, Harry.
我以为你很快就能调出解药
Well, I thought this called for a more practiced hand, sir.
我党得请老手出招比较好
Hello, darling. Fancy a drink?
亲党的，要喝什么吗?
Perhaps you're right.
也许你说得对
HARRY: I’m sorry, by the way, professor, about earlier today, our misunderstanding.
我要顺便为我的误解 部重地向你道歉
Oh, not at all. All water under the bridge, you know? Correct?
没事啦 过去的就让它过去，对吧?
l expect you're tired of it after all these years.
这刻多年后你一定早就屡伴了
All the questions about Voldemort.
这刻多关於佛地魔的问题
Don’t use that name.
别提起那名字 !
SLUGHORN: There you are, old boy. Bottoms up.
好了 ，乾了吧
-What's this? SLUGHORN: Tonic for the nerves.
-这是什么? -安定精神的解药
-What happened to me? -Love potion.
-我长生了什么事? -过情志药
A bloody strong one at that.
很强的才情者药
-l feel really bad. SLUGHORN: You need a pick-me-up, my boy.
-我感到头理脑腹 -你要喝些提神人饮吕
Got Butterbeer, wine, dazzling oak-matured mead.
我有奶油啤酒、葡萄酒 橡木桶酉的蜂蜜酒
l had other intentions for this, but I think, given the circumstances....
我本来想送给别人 不过以你的情况看来…
Here we are, Potter.
给他喝吧
To life!
数生命 !
HARRY: Ron.
沫因 !
Ron. Professor, do something.
教授，快想闪法 !
SLUGHORN: I don’t understand.
我不懂
HARRY: Come on, Ron, breathe.
加油，快呼吸
These girls, they’re gonna kill me.
那些女生会把我害死
Quick thinking on your part, Harry, using a bezoar.
你用羊次石当解药很陷明
You must be very proud of your student, Horace.
你一定为你的学生感到一全
I think we agree, Potter’s actions were heroic.
波特的行为是很英胃
The question is, why were they necessary?
问题是，有必要吧?
DUMBLEDORE: Why, indeed?
问得好
This appears to be a gift, Horace.
这瓶酒是送你的礼物
You don’t remember who gave you this bottle?
你不记得是谁送的?
Which, by the way, possesses remarkably subtle hints of licorice and cherry...
如果没被下毒，酒香应该有…
..-when not polluted with poison.
很淡的甘草和樱桃味道
SLUGHORN: Actually I had intended to give it as a gift myself.
我本来打算要当礼物送人
To whom, I might ask?
你要送给谁?
LAVENDER: Where is he?
他人呢?
Where's my Won-Won? Has he been asking for me?
我的荣荣呢 ? 他有没有找我?
What’s she doing here?
她在这里干嘛?
I might ask you the same question.
我个是要癌人同样的问题
I happen to be his girlfriend.
我是他的女朋友
l happen to be his friend.
我是他的…朋友
Don’t make me laugh. You haven't spoken in weeks.
真可笑，你们几星期没说过话
Il suppose you want to make up now that he’s all interesting.
我猜他现在演得很有趣 你就想跟他和好了
He’s been poisoned, you daft dimbo!
他被下了毒，大花瓶
And for the record, I've always found him interesting.
而且我一向都党得他很有趣
I'm here.
我在你身婉
RON: Uh.... Hermione....
妙恩
Oh, to be young, and to feel love’s keen sting.
年轻真好，可以感到爱的痛苦
Well, come away, everybody.
大家跟我走吧
Mr. Weasley is well tended.
卫斯理先生被照顾得很好
About time, don’t you think?
他们总算在一起了
Thank you.
谢谢和
Oh, shut up.
六噶啦
Stop it, Ron. You're making it snow.
住手，你让外面下雪了
Tell me how I broke up with Lavender again.
再告诉我是怎么和文姐分手
...she came to visit you in the hospital.
她来医院探稼你
And you talked.
你们谈了很久
I don’t believe it was a particularly long conversation.
我不敢相信你们会谈那广久
Don’t get me wrong, I’m bloody thrilled to be shot of her.
别误会，我很高典思掉她
It’s just she seems a bit put out.
只是她好像有点生气
Yes, she does, doesn’t she?
好像是吧
You say you don't remember anything from that night?
你说你不记得那晚的事?
Anything at all?
什么都不记得?9
There is something.
我记得一些事情
But it can’t be. I was completely boggled, wasn't I?
不过不可能 我当时得了失心况，不是吗?9
Right. Boggled.
对，失心疯
HERMIONE: Harry.
哈利
That's Katie.
那是凯嫌
Katie Bell.
凯嫌中冰
Katie. How are you?
凯娣，人好吗?
I know you're going to ask, Harry, but I don’t know who cursed me.
我知道你一定会阅 但是我不知道谁向我下加
I've been trying to remember, honestly.
我一直试著想记起来
But I just can't.
可是就是记不起来
Katie?
凯娣?
HARRY: I know what you did, Malfoy. You hexed her, didn't you?
图份，我知道是你搞的鬼 你向她下了吕，对吧?
Sectumsempra!
撕消三步狗
SNAPE: Vulnera Sanentur.
止角加
You have to get rid of it. Today.
你要马上把它丢掉
Take my hand.
抓住我的手
GINNY: We need to hide the Half-Blood Prince’s book...
我们要把混血王子的书藏起来
...where no one will ever find it, including you.
藏在速你都找不到的地方
-What was that?
-那是什么 ?
You never know what you'll find up here.
你永下不知道会找到什么
All right, close your eyes. That way you can't be tempted.
半上限晴 这样你就不会受到诱惑
That can stay hidden up here too, if you like.
这也可以藏在里面
So did you and Ginny do it, then?
你和金妮那个了哦，对吧?
What?
什么?
You know, hide the book?
把书藏起来呀
Oh, yeah.
噢，对啊
Still no luck with Slughorn, then, I take it?
史拉查还是什么都没说?
That's it. All l need’s a bit of luck.
没错，我只需要一点运气
HERMIONE: Well, how do you feel?
你觉得怎样了
Excellent.
好极了
Really excellent.
真的好极了
Remember...
记住…
...Slughorn usually eats early...
史拉画都很早吃饭
.. takes a walk, and then returns to his office.
散散步再回办公室
Right.
好
-l’m going down to Hagrid’s. -What?
-我要去找海格 -什么?
No, Harry, you've got to go and speak to Slughorn.
不，你得去找史拉兽
-We have a plan. HARRY: I know...
-我们都计划好了 -我知道
...but I've got a good feeling about Hagrid’s.
不过我圣海格有很强的直觉
I feel it’s the place to be tonight. Do you know what I mean?
我党得今晚应该去那里 你们懂我的意思吗?
-No. -Well, trust me, I know what I’m doing.
-不懂 -相信我，我知道…
Or Felix does.
我在做什么
Hi!
哈利!
Merlin’s beard, Harry!
梅林的明子，哈利 !
Sorry, sir. 1 should've announced myself. Cleared my throat, coughed.
抱歉，我应该先出个声 清清喉哟或咳咳嗽
You probably feared l was Professor Sprout.
你大概怕我是芽菜教授
Yes, I did, actually. What makes you think that?
是啊，你怎床会这广想呢?
Well, just the general behavior, sir.
你老是神神化化的
The sneaking around, the jumping when you saw me.
偷偷摸摸，看到我就嘛一跳
Are those Tentacula leaves, sir? They're very valuable, aren't they?
那是再触手某吗 ? 很值钱，圣吧?
Ten Galleons a leaf to the right buyer.
一月鞭子就能责十加隆
Not that I'm familiar with any such transactions, but one does hear rumors.
我不是对黑市交易很熟悉 只是总会匠到诡言
My own interests are purely academic, of course.
我纯粹是出於学本内趣
Personally, these plants always kind of freaked me out.
老实说，我超怕这些植物
SLUGHORN: How did you get out of the castle, Harry?
你是怎么离开十堡的?
HARRY: Through the front door, sir.
从正门走出来
I'm off to Hagrid’s. He’s a very dear friend...
我要去找海格，他是我好友…
..and I fancied paying him a visit.
我想去看看他
So if you don’t mind, I will be going now.
不好意思，我这就走了
Harry!
哈利!
-Sir? -It’s nearly nightfall.
-教授? -就快天黑了
Surely you realize I can’t allow you to go roaming the grounds by yourself.
我可不能让你自己在外面尖走
Well, then, by all means, come along, sir.
你就仙管一起来吧
SLUGHORN: Harry, I must insist you accompany me...
哈利，我必须坚持要你… 隘我回到十堡
HARRY: That would be counterproductive, sir.
这不会有什么好包
And what makes you say that?
你为什么这庆说?
No idea.
我也不知道
Horace.
赫瑞司
Merlin’s beard. Is that an actual Acromantula?
梅林的昱子 那是真的虹蛛精吧?
A dead one, I think, sir.
他应该死了
Good God.
老天答
Dear fellow, however did you manage to kill it?
好像伏，你是怎庆角死他的?
Kill it? Me oldest friend, he was.
杀死他? 他可是我的老朋友
-I'm so sorry, I didn’t-- -Don't worry yourself, you're not alone.
-很遗憾，我不知道… -没关像，不只是你怕歼蛛
Seriously misunderstood creatures, spiders are.
其实效蛛一直受到误解
It’s the eyes, I reckon. They unnerve some folk.
只是他们的眼珠很嘛人
Not to mention the pincers.
还有他们的瑜
Yeah, I reckon that too.
我猜也是吧
Hagrid, the last thing I wish to be is indelicate...
海格，我不想在伤口漫由
...but Acromantular venom is uncommonly rare.
不过蛛精再液非常珍贵稀少
Would you allow me to extract a vial or two?
你能让我革取一，两管吗?
Purely for academic purposes, you understand.
纯粹是为了学街研究
Well, don’t suppose it’s going to do him much good now, is it?
我猜反正也救不了它了
My thoughts exactly.
我为了遇到这征事
Always have a ampoule or two about my person for just such occasions as this.
随时随地都揣带著试管
Old Potions Master's habit, you know.
老一派魔药学教授的悄惯
l wish you could’ve seen him in his prime.
真希望你能见到他的全盛时期
Magnificent, he was. Just magnificent.
太雄伟了，他太雄仿了
Oh, dear.
天啊
-Would you like me to say a few words? -Yes.
-你要我说些悼文吐? -好吧
He had a family, I trust?
他应该有家人吧?
Farewell....
永别了…
Aragog.
阿辣哥
Farewell, Aragog...
永别了，阿辣哥…
... king of the arachnids.
菌蛛之王
Your body will decay...
你的躯体也许会腐壤
...but your spirit lingers on.
但是精神永下长存
And your human friends find solace in the loss they have sustained.
你的人类朋友为了得到安古 好好地将你安葬
I had him from an egg, you know. Tiny little thing he was when he hatched.
他悲伤到速魔杖都断成两节 我从他是颗卵就在他身逮
No bigger than a Pekinese. A Pekinese, mind you.
他孵出来时膛很小，没比一焦北京犬大 一焦北京犬哦
How sweet. I once had a fish. Francis. He was very dear to me.
真感人，我养丙一条鱼法苦西 我真的很直他
One afternoon I came downstairs, and he'd vanished.
有一天下午我走到楼下 他就不见了
-That’s very odd, isn’t it? -It is, isn’t it?
-很奇怪，不是吗? -是啊，不是唉?
But that’s life, 1 suppose.
不过我猜生命就是这魔脆弱
You go along and then suddenly, poof!
你活著活著就突然不见了
It was a student who gave me Francis.
法苦西是一个学生送我的
One spring afternoon I discovered a bowl on my desk...
一个春天午后 我在桌上发现一个急秸
...With just a few inches of clear water in it.
只装了红叶高的清水
And floating on the surface was a flower petal.
一月花瓣浮在水面
As I watched, it sank.
我看著它沉下去
Just before it reached the bottom...
它沉到拭底之前…
. it transformed...
就化身成…
...into a wee fish.
一休小小的急儿…
It was beautiful magic.
好美的魔法
Wondrous to behold.
令人吧为观目
The flower petal had come from a lily.
那月花准来自一条百合花
Your mother.
你的母亲
The day I came downstairs...
我走到楼下的那天…
...the day the bowl was empty...
急红是空的那天
...-was the day your mother....
就是你母亲…
I know why you're here.
我知道你为什么来这壬
But I can’t help you.
不过我不能帮你
It would ruin me.
我的名历会被毁掉
Do you know why I survived, professor?
你知道我是怎庆活下来的吗?
The night I got this?
我被刺伤的那晚?
Because of her.
全是因为她
Because she sacrificed herself.
她为了救我以牲自己
Because she refused to step aside.
因为她不肯让开
Because her love was more powerful than Voldemort.
因为她的党比佛地魔更强大
-Don't say his name. -I'm not afraid of the name, professor.
-别说他的名字 -我区不怕这个名字
I'm going to tell you something.
我要告诉你一件事
Something others have only guessed at.
其他人只猜到的事情
It’s true.
是真的
lam the Chosen One.
我是被选中的人
Only I can destroy him, but in order to do so...
只有我能氛毁他，但是…
...l need to know what Tom Riddle asked you years ago in your office...
我要知道汤姆瑞斗多年前
..-and I need to know what you told him.
问了你什么，你告诉他什么
Be brave like my mother.
像我母亲一样勇敢
Otherwise, you disgrace her.
不然你就会让她蒙闭
Otherwise, she died for nothing.
不然她就白白粕牧
Otherwise, the bowl will remain empty forever.
不然急红永焉都会是空的
Please, don’t think badly of me when you see it.
你看到以和后请不要怪我
You've no idea what he was like, even then.
你不知道他那时候有多可怕
RIDDLE: l was in the library the other night...
前线天晚上我在…
...in the Restricted Section...
图书馆的禁区
..and I read something rather odd about a bit of rare magic.
我读到一个罕见魔法的段落
It’s called, as 1 understand it...
以我的理解，它叫…
a Horcrux.
分电体
-l beg your pardon? -Horcrux.
-你说什么? -分赴胡
l came across the term while reading...
我无意问读到这个字
...and I didn’t fully understand it.
但我不能完全了解这总思
I'm not sure what you were reading, Tom, but this is very dark stuff, very dark indeed.
我不确定你读的是什么 不过这是非常黑暗的魔法
Which is...
所以…
...why I came to you.
我才会来找你
A Horcrux is an object in which a person has concealed part of their soul.
分震硒是一个人… 隐藏一部份起魂的东西
But I don’t understand how that works, sir.
我不了解它该怎订用
One splits one’s soul and hides part of it in an object.
你把起魂分裂藏进一样东西
By doing so, you're protected, should you be attacked and your body destroyed.
就算你的身体被摧毁 你的赴魂仍然受到保护
Protected?
保护 ?
That part of your soul that is hidden lives on.
你隐藏的起魂会活下去
In other words, you cannot die.
换句话说，你永天不会死
And how does one split his soul, sir?
一个人要怎太分裂才魂?
SLUGHORN: I think you already know the answer to that, Tom.
你应该知道答案了“，汤姆
Murder.
角死别人
Yes.
没错
Killing rips the soul apart. It is a violation against nature.
因为这是这背自然的事
RIDDLE: Can you only split the soul once? For instance, isn’t seven...?
只能分裂赴魂一次吗? 比如说，七次不是…
Seven?
七欢?
Merlin’s beard, Tom. Isn't it bad enough to consider killing one person?
梅林的明子 ! 杀一个人还不金那奈吧?
To rip the soul into seven pieces....
把韦魂分成七志
This is all hypothetical, isn’t it, Tom? All academic?
只是学生性的假设，和对吧?
It'll be our little secret.
这是我们的小秘密
HARRY: Sir.
校长
This is beyond anything I imagined.
这比我想像得更帮
You mean to say he succeeded, sir, in making a Horcrux?
你是说他成功抽造了分赴体?
Oh, yes, he succeeded, all right. And not just once.
没错，他不只分裂了一次
What are they exactly?
分直硒到底是什么 ?
Could be anything. Most commonplace of objects.
什么都有可能，最常见的东西
A ring, for example.
比如说，一焦戒指
Or a book.
或是一本着
-Tom Riddle’s diary. -It's a Horcrux, yes.
-混姆瑞斗的日记
Four years ago, when you saved Ginny's life...
四年前，当你在消失的密室…
...in the Chamber of Secrets, you brought me this.
救了金妮卫斯理，你给我这个
I knew this was a different kind of magic.
非常黑暗，力量强大 直到今晚我才知道有多强大
-The ring? -Belonged to Voldemort’s mother.
-那焦戒指? -佛地魔母亲的戒指
Difficult to find. Even more difficult to destroy.
想找到它很困准 想挫俩它更困准
But if you could find them all, if you did destroy each Horcrux....
如果能把全部都找到 挫角每一个分韦体
One destroys Voldemort.
就能挫毁佛地魔
But how would you find them? They could be hidden anywhere.
该怎庆找到它们 ? 它们可能藏在任何地方
True. But magic, especially dark magic...
没错 但是魔法，尤其是黑魔法…
.. leaves traces.
都会留下痕跻
It’s where you've been going, isn’t it, sir?
你郊开学校
-When you leave the school? -Yes.
-就是去找它们? -没错
And I think perhaps I may have found another.
我可能发现了第三个分韦体
But this time, I cannot hope to destroy it alone.
但这次我不可能一个人扫毁它
Once again, I must ask too much of you, Harry.
我又得要求太多，请你帮忙
SNAPE: Have you ever considered that you ask too much...
你有没有起过你要求他太多
...that you take too much for granted?
也把他视为理所当然?
Has it ever crossed your brilliant mind that I don’t want to do this anymore?
伟大的校长，你有没有想过 我也许不想再继续下去 ?
Whether it has or hasn't is irrelevant.
我有没有想过不重要
I will not negotiate with you, Severus. You agreed. Nothing more to discuss.
我不想和你事吟，赛佛勒斯 你答应了，没什么好说的
Oh, Harry.
哈利
You need a shave, my friend.
你要弟个明子
You know, at times, I forget how much you've grown.
你知道，有时候 我都忘了你长得有多大了
At times, I still see the small boy from the cupboard.
有时候我还看到你是个小孩
Forgive my mawkishness, Harry.
原该我这广多稚善感
I'm an old man.
我是个老头外
You still look the same to me, sir.
你看起来跟以前一样
Just like your mother, you're unfailingly kind.
你跟你母疯一样永不放宗
A trait people never fail to undervalue, I'm afraid.
没有人会忽略这种特性
The place to which we journey tonight is extremely dangerous.
我们今晚去的地方很危险
I promised you could accompany me, and I stand by that promise.
我答应你陪我去就不会反悔
But there is one condition:
但是有一个人条件
You must obey every command I give you, without question.
你必须服从我每个命令
Yes, sir.
是的，校长
You do understand what I’m saying?
你明白我说的话吗?
Should I tell you to hide, you hide.
我要你躲起来，你就躲起来
Should I tell you to run, you run.
我要你跑，你就跑
Should I tell you to abandon me and save yourself, you must do so.
我要你丢下我救你自己 你一定要这硒做
Your word, Harry.
你要答应我，哈利
Take my arm.
担住我的手辟
Sir, 1 thought you couldn't Apparate within Hogwarts.
我以为在校内不能用现影征
Well, being me has its privileges.
校长还是有一些特权
DUMBLEDORE: This is the place.
就是这地方
Oh, yes.
没错
This place has known magic.
有人在这壬施展过魔法
-Sir! -In order to gain passage...
-校长 ! -想进去…
...Payment must be made.
就要付出代价
Payment intended to weaken any intruder.
这代价会让入侵者变弱
-You should've let me, sir. -No, Harry.
-不，哈利
Your blood’s much more precious than mine.
你的血比我的血更宝贵
Voldemort will not have made it easy to discover his hiding place.
佛地魔不会轻易让人 找到他的藏身之处
He will have put certain defenses in position.
他一定会设下陷阱
Careful.
小心
There it is.
就是那里
The only question is, how do we get there?
问题是，该怎么过去 ?
If you would, Harry.
哈利，用力拉
Do you think the Horcrux is in there, sir?
分起体在这里面吧?
It has to be drunk.
一定要喝才行
All of it has to be drunk.
全都喝完才会现形
You remember the conditions on which I brought you with me?
记得我带你来的条件吗?
This potion might paralyze me.
这本水可能让我疗瘦
Might make me forget why I’m here.
也许害我忘了为何而来
Might cause me so much pain that I beg for relief.
让我痛苦到想要以死解辽
You are not to indulge these requests.
你绝对不能做任何事
It’s your job, Harry, to make sure I keep drinking this potion.
你要负责确定我喝完病水
Even if you have to force it down my throat.
就算你要灌进我的喉噬
-Understood? -Why can’t I drink it, sir?
-明白吗? -为什么不能让我喝 ?
Because I am much older, much cleverer, and much less valuable.
因为我太老，太狂点 太没有价值了
Your good health, Harry.
祝你身体健康，哈利
Professor.
教授 !
HARRY: Professor, can you hear me?
教授 ! 你由得见吗?
No. Don't.
不，不要
You have to keep drinking, like you said. Remember?
你得像你说的一直喝
DUMBLEDORE: Stop. -It will stop. It will stop...
-停下来 -只要你喝完…
-...but only if you keep drinking. -Please, don’t make me.
-一切就会结束 -求求你 ! 别融我喝 !
-I'm sorry, sir. -Please.
-对不起 -求求你
-Kill me. Kill me! -No!
-和角了我吧 ! -不!吐!
It’s all my fault.
全都是我的错
HARRY: Just one more, sir. One more, and then I promise...
再喝一杯，然后我就保证…
...[ promise I'll do what you say.
你要我做什么我就做
-l promise. -No.
-我保证 --不
Please.
拜旗 !
Harry.
哈利
Water.
我要喝水
You did it, sir.
你办到了
Look.
你看
Harry.
哈利
Water.
水
Aguamenti.
水水喷
DUMBLEDORE: Water.
我要水
Lumos.
路摸思
Lumos Maxima!
魔杖发光 !
DUMBLEDORE: Harry.
哈利
Sectumsempra!
撕消三步角 !
-Stupefy! DUMBLEDORE: Harry.
-绚绚森 ! -哈利
DUMBLEDORE: Harry.
哈利
Partis Temporus!
火火去 !
Go to your houses. No dawdling.
回去你的学院 别拖拖拉拉 !
We need to get you to the hospital wing, sir, to Madam Pomfrey.
我们得送你到医院 去找麻芮夫人
No.
不
Severus. Severus is who I need.
去找赛佛勒斯 我需要赛佛勒斯
Wake him. Tell him what happened.
叫醒他，告诉他发生什么事
Speak to no one else.
别跟任何人说
Severus, Harry.
去找赛佛勒斯，哈利
Hide yourself below, Harry.
散在下面
Don't speak or be seen by anybody without my permission.
没有我允许 不准跟任何人见面或说话
Whatever happens, it's imperative you stay below.
不管发生什么事 你一定要躲在下面
Harry, do as I say.
哈利，匠我的话
Trust me.
相信我
Good evening, Draco.
你好，践哥
What brings you here on this fine spring evening?
这麻美好的夜晚，你跑来干嘛
Who else is here? I heard you talking.
还有谁? 我聘到说话声
DUMBLEDORE: I often talk aloud to myself. I find it extraordinarily useful.
我常常自言自语 我党得很有用
Have you been whispering to yourself, Draco?
你有没有拥心自半?9
Draco...
践哥
. -...you are no assassin. -How do you know what I am?
-你不是当刺窜的料 -你怎麻知道?
I've done things that would shock you.
我做过会嘛死你的事
Like cursing Katie Bell and hoping that in return she'd bear a cursed necklace to me?
像是对凯娣中南下加 希望她会把下咒的项鱼给我?
Replacing a bottle of mead with one laced with poison?
或是让我误喝下了毒的蜂蜜酒
Forgive me, Draco.
原该我这刻说
I cannot help feeling these actions are so weak...
你的这些行动太差盈了…
...your heart can't really have been in them.
所以你其实蔡不想杀我
He trusts me. I was chosen.
他信任我 ! 我是被选中的人 !
DUMBLEDORE: Then I shall make it easy for you.
那我就让你轻用一点
Expelliarmus!
去去，武器走!
DUMBLEDORE: Very good. Very good.
很好，非常好
You're not alone.
你蔚不是一个人
There are others.
还有其他人
How?
你是怎庆做到的?
The vanishing cabinet in the Room of Requirement.
菌谭室里的消失杭郴
-l've been mending it. DUMBLEDORE: Let me guess.
-我一直在修理它 -让我猜…
It has a sister. A twin.
它有个姊妹 它是双胞胎
In Borgin and Burkes. They form a passage.
在波金与伯克氏店形成通道
DUMBLEDORE: Ingenious.
真隐明
Draco...
忠哥…
.. years ago, I knew a boy who made all the wrong choices.
多年前我认识一个… 做出各种错误玩择的男孩
-Please let me help you. -l don’t want your help!
-请你让我帮助你 -我不要你的帮助
Don't you understand? I have to do this.
你逮不懂? 我一定要这广做
Il have to kill you.
我非杀你不可
Or he’s gonna kill me.
不然他就会角死我
Well, look what we have here.
看看这是怎订回事
Well done, Draco.
干得好，践哥
DUMBLEDORE: Good evening, Bellatrix.
人好，贝拉
I think introductions are in order, don’t you?
你最好介绍你的朋友
BELLATRIX: Love to, Albus, but I’m afraid we're all on a bit of a tight schedule.
我也很想，阿不思 不过恐怕时间不欧了
Do it.
下手吧 !
GREYBACK: He doesn’t have the stomach, just like his father.
他跟他老苞一样没有种
Let me finish him in my own way.
让我用我的方法解决他吧
BELLATRIX: No! The Dark Lord was clear, the boy is to do it.
不，黑魔王说得很清楚 一定要让这孩子下手
This is your moment. Do it.
这是你的时刻，下手吧
Go on, Draco.
快点呀，践哥
Now!
快下手
SNAPE: No.
不
DUMBLEDORE: Severus.
赛佛勒斯
Please.
求求你
Avada Kedavra.
阿哇咀喀咀啦 !
Yeah!
太好了 !
BELLATRIX: Hagrid! Hello?
海格 ! 你在吗 ?
HARRY: Snape! He trusted you!
石内卜，他信任你!
SNAPE: Go on.
快走吧,
incarcerous.
绚继禁 !
Fight back! You coward, fight back!
反击呀 ! 你这情夫 !
SNAPE: No! He belongs to the Dark Lord.
不，他属於黑魔王
Sectumsempra!
撕消三步角 !
You dare use my own spells against me, Potter?
你竟到用我的魔响对付我?
Yes.
没错
I'm the Half-Blood Prince.
我就是混血王子
McGONAGALL: Potter...
波特…
...if you should have the need to talk to someone....
你想谈可以跟我谈
You should know, Professor Dumbledore...
你该知道，部不多利教授…
...you meant a great deal to him.
你对他来说很重要
HERMIONE: Do you think he would've done it?
你认为他会下手吗?
Draco?
践哥吗?
HARRY: No.
不会
No, he was lowering his wand.
不，他把魔杖放下来
In the end, it was Snape.
最后是石内卜角了他
It was always Snape.
一直都是石内下
And I did nothing.
我印什笨都没有做
It’s fake.
这是假的
Open it.
打开来
“To the Dark Lord. I know I will be dead long before you read this...
“致黑魔王 我知道你读到时我早就死了…”
...but want you to know that it was I who discovered your secret.
“不过我要你知道 是我发现你的秘密“
I have stolen the real Horcrux and intend to destroy it as soon as I! can.
“我偷走了真正的分二朵 打算侯快消减它^
l face death in the hope that when you meet your match...
“我冒著生命危险 希望你遇到你的艇手…”
...you will be mortal once more.
“而你也将再度成为凡人”
R.A.B."
R.A.B.
Don’t know.
我不知道是谁
But whoever they are, they have the real Horcrux.
不管怎榜，他有真正的分性朵
Which means it was all a waste.
这代表我们白费心机
All of it.
这一切都白白浪费
Ron's okay with it, you know.
上因倒是能接受
You and Ginny.
你和金妮在一起
But if 1 were you, when he’s around, I'd keep the snogging to a minimum.
不过要是他在劣冰 你们最好别一直亲踢
HARRY: I'm not coming back, Hermione.
我不会回来，妙果
I've got to finish whatever Dumbledore started.
我得完成性不多利的任务
And I don’t know where that'll lead me...
我不知道我会到哪里
...but ll let you and Ron know where I am when I can.
可以的话我告诉你和和楷思
I've always admired your courage, Harry.
我一向很佩服你的勇气
But sometimes, you can be really thick.
不过有时候你真的很固执
You don’t really think you're going to be able...
你真以为你能靠自己
...to find all those Horcruxes by yourself, do you?
找到全部的分韦体?
You need us, Harry.
你需要我们
HARRY: I never realized how beautiful this place was.
我从来没发现这地方有多美
[ENGLISH SDH]
[CANTONESE ]